<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./_c74_ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<c74object name="JamomaRampLib">
	
    <digest>
        Jamoma Ramp Library
    </digest>

    <description>
        Library of units that in different ways trigger updates of values during ramps from one value or set of values to another.<br />
		<br />
		Some ramp units have further properties influencing the way values are updated. These properties can be set and queried.  <br />
		<br />
		The JamomaRampLib, when queried, will provide information on available ramp units, available properties for each ramp unit, 
		current unit used, and the state of properties for the current ramp unit.
    </description>


	<!--METADATA-->
	
	<metadatalist>
		
		<metadata name="author">
			jamoma.org
		</metadata>
		
		<metadata name="tag">
			Jamoma
		</metadata>
		
		<metadata name="tag">
			Max
		</metadata>
		
		<metadata name="tag">
			Data
		</metadata>
		
		<metadata name="tag">
			Library
		</metadata>
		
	</metadatalist>




	<!--SEEALSO-->
	
	<seealsolist>
		
		<seealso name="JamomaDataspaceLib">
			The Jamoma Dataspace Library
		</seealso>		
		<seealso name="JamomaFunctionLib">
			The Jamoma Function Library
		</seealso>
		
		<seealso name="jcom.message">
			Handling messages in Jamoma modules
		</seealso>

		<seealso name="jcom.parameter">
			Handling parameters in Jamoma modules
		</seealso>
		
		<seealso name="jcom.ramp">
			Ramping from one value to another, using the Jamoma RampLib and FunctionLib
		</seealso>
		
		<seealso name="bline">
			Event-driven multi-segment line object
		</seealso>
		
		<seealso name="line">
			Output numbers in a ramp from one value to another
		</seealso>
		
		<seealso name="line~">
			Linear ramp generator
		</seealso>
		<seealso name="setclock">
			Control the clock speed of timing objects remotely
		</seealso>
		
	</seealsolist>


	<!--MISC-->

	<misc name="Ramp Units">
	
		<entry name="async">
			<description>
				<br />
				<br />
				Asyncronuous (event-driven) ramping driven by bangs passed to module (hub) or Max messages passed to leftmost signal inlet.
				In video modules the <m>async</m> ramp unit can be used to update paramerters only when a new Jitter matrix is 
				about to be calculated. <br />
				<br />
			</description>
		</entry>
		
		<entry name="none">
			<description>
				<br />
				<br />
				A non-ramping unit. This ramp unit just sets the value immediately.<br />
				<br />
			</description>
		</entry>

		<entry name="queue">
			<description>
				<br />
				<br />
				Ramping unit using the Max queue in order to update as often as possible without getting in the way of timed processes.<br />
				<br />
			</description>
		</entry>

		<entry name="scheduler">
			<description>
				<br />
				<br />
				Ramping unit providing updated values at regular and timed ticks, using the Max scheduler.<br />
				<br />
				Properties:<br />
				<br />
				• <m>clock</m>: The <m>clock</m> property, followed by the name of an existing <o>setclock</o> object, sets the <m>scheduler</m> 
				ramp unit to be controlled by that <o>setclock</o> object rather than by Max’s internal millisecond clock. 
				If no argument is provided for the <m>clock</m> property, the <m>scheduler</m> ramp unit falls back to using Max’s regular 
				millisecond clock. <br />
				• <m>granularity</m>: The time grain (output interval) between updated values. <br />	
				<br />
			</description>
		</entry>			

	</misc>
	
</c74object>